<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>ZeGrapher.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>
  <name>ZeGrapher</name>
  <summary>Fast and intuitive math graphing software</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
        ZeGrapher is an ergonomic, intuitive and fast software for plotting
        mathematical objects (functions, sequences, parametric equations)
        and experimental data on the plane (with polynomial fitting, CSV
        import/export).
    </p>
    <p>
        Here is what Zegrapher v3.0 can offer you:<br/>
        <ul>
            <li>Visualize up to six functions simultaneously. All the usual functions can be called: they're all written on a virtual keyboard. <br/>
                On a given function, others can be called, so it is possible to associate or compose functions.</li>
            <li>Numerical sequence plotting, they can be defined by a recurrent relation or explicitly.</li>
            <li>Parametric equation plotting. The curves can be animated, with adjustable smoothness (frame rate) and speed (ms per step).</li>
            <li>Experimental data plot and polynomial fit (regression). Data can be imported/exported from a CSV file.
            <li>Parametric plot for functions, sequences and parametric equations: the parameter symbol to use is "k".</li>
            <li>Plot tangents: they can be moved and resized simply with the mouse.</li>
            <li>Plot derivatives and antiderviatives.</li>
            <li>Print the graph, with the following options :</li>
            <ul>
                <li>Choose the size and the position of the graph on the sheet.</li>
                <li>Print in color or gray-scale.</li>
                <li>Export on a PDF file.</li>
            </ul>
            <li>Export to all common image formats (png, jpeg, tiff, gif...).</li>
            <li>Display a table of values with different options.</li>
            <li>Navigate on the graph :</li>
            <ul>
                <li>Select a curve to display the coordinates of its points.</li>
                <li>Zoom/unzoom on each axis separately or together, with the mouse on a point, or on a rectangular region.</li>
                <li>Move the graph.</li>
            </ul>
            <li>Customize the presentation :</li>
            <ul>
                <li>Change all the colors: axes, background, functions...</li>
                <li>Chose the program's and graph's font</li>
                <li>Adjust the plotting precision. Note that it will also affect rendering speed.</li>
                <li>Show/hide a grid.</li>
                <li>Activate/deactivate curves' smoothing.</li>
                <li>Plot the graph on an orthonormal basis.</li>
            </ul>
        </ul>
    </p>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://zegrapher.com/screenshots/2g.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://zegrapher.com/screenshots/3g.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://zegrapher.com/screenshots/4g.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://zegrapher.com/screenshots/7g.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://zegrapher.com/screenshots/12g.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://zegrapher.com/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/AdelKS/ZeGrapher/issues</url>
  <update_contact>eclipseo_at_fedoraproject.org</update_contact>
</component>
